Hi, and welcome back.
嗨，欢迎回来
We're gonna have a look at Razor Pages in this model.
在这一节中，我们将来讨论 Razor Pages
We had a look at it a bit before where we introduced you to the concept of a page.
在我们向你介绍页面概念之前，让我们来先来看下
And now we are gonna have a look at it outside of Visual Studio Code and the command line
除了 Visual Studio Code 和命令行之外的操作方式
we are gonna get started on Visual Studio
例如使用 Visual Studio
Right, so we are even doing our stuff in Visual Studio Code，you can see here
是的，跟着我们看到这里的小伙伴们应该知道我们已经在 Visual Studio Code 中完成了一些工作
we goofed around a little bit and we made a couple of pages
并且完成了一些页面
You remember though that we started from an empty template.
你还记得我们从一个空模板开始的步骤嘛
Yeah.
当然
So we went from nothing, we went from a Hello World console app into something with pages.
我们从无到有，从一个 Hello World 的控制台应用程序到一个包含一些页面的应用
I'm gonna close Visual Studio Code and I am going to go out here to Visual Studio proper
我将关闭 Visual Studio Code 然后在这里可以找到适合的 Visual Studio 版本
Visual Studio for Windows
比如 Visual Studio for Windows
Yep.
是的
You might be on Visual Studio for Mac if you're on a Mac.
如果你使用的是Mac，也可以使用 Visual Studio for Mac
And in this particular case I'm gonna be using Visual Studio 2017 Community
现在，我将使用 Visual Studio 2017 的社区版
you can go and get this at VisualStudio.com
你可以在 VisualStudio.com 上获取相关信息
For free.
而且此版本是免费的
For free, it works just nice, it's great, Visual Studio Community has a couple
免费，这就很棒，可 Visual Studio 的社区版对
of small restrictions based on the size of your company.
公司来说还是有一些小限制
But if you're doing this as an open source person or as a person who's learning
但是，如果你作为开源开发者或用于学习
Visual Studio Community is effectively pro.
Visual Studio 的社区版已经足够专业了
It's effectively the pro version, let's you have extensions, it's great little tool.
它实际上是一个可扩展的专业版，这是一个很棒的小工具
All right, so what I wanna do is, you can see just to familiarize yourself with
所以我想做的是，你能在这看到一些熟悉的
the UI here I've got some recents and things, I've got New Project.
界面，最近活动、新建项目等
You can say, Create New Project, on the left hand side
你可以在左侧创建新项目，可能你看到内容会和这里不同
you may see different stuff depending on what you installed.
这取决于你安装的内容
When I ran the installer for Visual Studio, I set up for the web for workload it's called the Workload.
当我运行 Visual Studio 的安装程序时，我把 Web 设置为了工作负载
You might have Android you might not,
你可能没有 Android
but you wanna make sure that you have the .Net core web workload.
但是你应该确保安装了 .Net Core Web 的工作负载
Quick question, you mentioned the Visual Studio installer
问一下，你提到 Visual Studio 安装程序
that does come when you download Visual Studio?
是在下载 Visual Studio 时会用到吗？
Yeah, good point, let me bring that up, when you install it you're gonna get this application,
问得好，让我把它打开，当你安装后你会看到这个应用程序
this is Visual Studio installer coming up here, one moment.
这是就是 Visual Studio 安装程序
And the installer is modular, so it'll come up like this.
安装程序是模块化的，它会是这样一种形式
And if I say Modify, you can run the installer multiple times
如果点击修改，你就可以多次运行安装程序
you can run installer after you've installed Visual Studio if you wanted to add other stuff.
若你还想添加其他内容，也可以在安装 Visual Studio 后再次运行安装程序
See look, even the installer itself wants to update, so right now just coincidentally
你看，即使安装程序本身需要更新，当然这只是巧合
the installer has new stuff that it wants to give me.
安装程序也会有一些新东西
So it's gonna go and update itself, while it's doing that
它会自动更新，就像现在这样
you download this thing called a bootstrapper.
你在下载这个叫做 bootstrapper 的东西
It's a tiny little installer that goes and gets the things that you want.
这是一个小小的安装程序，可以获取你想要的东西
Visual Studio could be quite large if you installed everything or it could install in 20 minutes
如果你安装了所有内容， Visual Studio 可能会非常大，如果想在在20分钟内完成安装的话
if you just wanted to do web apps or you just wanted to do Windows apps.
只安装 Web 应用程序，或者 Windows 应用程序就可以了
So this allows you to customize your install.
也就是说，它允许你自定义安装
Exactly, and the things that you customize them with are called workloads
确切地说，你自定义选择的东西称为工作负载
like the cloud workload or the mobile device workload.
如云工作负载或移动设备工作负载
There you go, it just updated itself
让我们继续吧，它已经完成了自动更新
you can see that I have at the time of this recording, Visual Studio Community 15.4.
你可以看到我在录制时，版本号为 Visual Studio Community 15.4
You should make sure that you have at least that or higher.
你应该确保你的版本应该至少比这个更高
If I click on Modify it's gonna give me some more choices.
如果我点击修改它会给我一些更多的选择
And I'm doing this of course after the fact I picked Universal Windows, I picked .NET desktop I picked ASP.Net
在这次课程前，我安装了通用 Windows 应用、 .NET 桌面程序以及 ASP.NET
But you can see so many other options, you have Python, Node, Data Science.
但是你可以看到很多其他的选择，比如说有 Python 、 Node 、 Data Science 之类的
And I could add these things afterwards
我可以在之后再添加这些模块
so if I wanted to do Linux development C++ I would click that and it will update and tell me.
所以如果我想在 Linux 下开发 C++ ，我会选中它，然后就会提示我更新
Right now, it's thinking about how much more it needs to download in order to get me that stuff.
现在，它正在计算下载这些东西需要多少容量
And then from within that you can go into individual components and pick on the specific things that you want,
然后从这里你可以选择单个组件或选择你想要的特定工具
so you see, I've selected #F as well.
所以你看，我也选择了 F#
This can be run multiple times
这一流程可以运行多次
and I just wanted to point out that I ran it and installed the web workload.
我只想指出我运行它并安装了 Web 工作负载
So installing the web workload when went
所以在安装好 Web 工作负载之后
File > New > Project is what gives me this choice here for saying, Web pages.
你将会在文件 > 新建 > 项目下看到 Web 页面的选项
So Visual C# > Web pages, and I've got the ASP.NET Web Applications using the .NET Framework,
到 Visual C# > Web 页面，我看到使用 .NET Framework 的 ASP.NET Web 应用程序
the full framework that comes with Windows.
Windows 附带完整的 .NET Framework 框架
Or ASP.NET Core Web Apps, which work on of course Linux and Mac
或者是 ASP.NET Core Web Apps ，它们当然适用于 Linux\Mac
and Windows, which is what we're doing today
以及 Windows ，这就是我们今天所要用的
-All right -Good stuff
-好的 -很好
I'm gonna double-click on that, I've said File > New Project and it's gonna pop up a dialogue here.
我要双击它，根据 文件 > 新项目 ，它会在这里弹出对话
You're gonna wanna double check this dropdown
你需要仔细检查这个下拉列表
you might have its default to core 1.0 or 1.1, you're gonna wanna be 2.0 or higher.
你的默认设置可能是 core 1.0 或 1.1 ，而你需要使用 2.0 或更高
You'll notice that the icons change based on what you pick, I could make Angular apps, React.js apps
你会注意到这些图标会根据你选择的内容而改变
I could make full Model View Controller applications.
我可以制作 Angular 应用程序， React.js 应用程序，或是完整的 MVC 应用程序
We're just gonna say Web App, which is the default, this gives us both Razor Pages that we're doing today.
这里我们只用 Web App ，这是默认设置，它为我们提供了今天将要用的 Razor Pages
And of course, Razor Pages are a part of or built on top of Model View Controller
当然，Razor Pages 是 MVC 的一部分或者说基于 MVC
so it's really the best choice for everybody, the most recent project template.
所以它会是每个人的最佳选择，即最新的项目模板
And if you were doing that from the command line, do you remember what the command was for that?
如果你是在命令行中执行此操作，你还记得该怎么用吗？
-Razor -dotnet new razor -exactly
-Razor -dotnet new razor -很好
Okay, so I'll double click on that.
好的，而在这里我只需双击它
And when we create that, we're gonna watch the right-hand side over here where it says Solution Explorer.
当我们创建它时，我们将在右侧看到解决方案资源管理器
This will get you the same output as if you had said, dotnet new razor
这和你使用 dotnet new razor 获得的是相同的效果
this is important that dotnet new web or dotnet new mvc.
这对 dotnet new web 和 dotnet new mvc 来说是很重要的
It's the same experience.
体验是一致的
It's the same experience, you don't wanna have a different experience
对，这是一样的体验，你不会希望使用 Visual Studio code 的人
for Visual Studio code people than you do for Visual Studio proper people.
拥有与 Visual Studio 的专业人员有不同的体验
But templating does match cuz before you had to use a bit of yeoman over in one place.
且输出的模板都是相匹配的，而在之前你需要在某个地方使用 yeoman 来实现
Right, all templating is matched and it's nice and clean.
对，所有模板都是匹配的，这样既便利又整洁
Here's a little helper page that shows up there, but we're gonna zoom over here
在这显示了一个小的帮助页面，但让我们把这里放大
and see how Visual Studio for Windows expresses itself.
看看 Visual Studio for Windows 是如何展示这个项目的
You can see we've got a couple more pages than before, we've got an About and a Contact page.
你可以看到我们得到了比以前更多的页面，我们看到有 About 以及 Contact 页面
And where would those pads be, given what we learned about Razor pads?
那根据我们对 Razor 路由的了解，这些页面的路由应该是什么？
/About, /Context, /Error, /Index would be default.
/About ， /Context ， /Error ，其中 /Index 将是默认页面
Index would be default, exactly, right, now interestingly, these have something underneath them.
很好， Index 页面将会是默认页面，现在有趣的是，在这些页面的下方还有东西
So these are the code behinds or the page models, that's the page
这是在页面之后的代码，或者叫做页面模型，这是页面，而这是页面模型
and that's the page model and they've nested those.
它们会镶嵌在一起
This is an important little thing to point out
这里有个细节值得注意一下
let's look at this in Windows Explorer just to make sure, if I say open in Windows Explorer.
让我们在资源管理器中再确认一下这些文件，让我这选择 在资源管理器中打开
It should appear as two separate files?
它应该显示为两个单独的文件？
They are two separate files.
它们是两个独立的文件
So here's Index and Index.cshtml, they are clearly two separate files.
这里有 Index 以及 Index.cshtml ，它们显然是两个独立的文件
But it's convenient and it gives you a sense of the relationship
但在这却很方便，通过 Visual Studio 中的资源管理器
between the files that the Solution Explorer in Visual Studio will go and nest them.
你可以清楚地看到文件之间的关系并将其隐藏起来
So could you think about as the car and then the engine?
所以你能联想到汽车和发动机之间的关系吗？
Yeah, you could do that, anything that is any hierarchy, and then beneath that .cs
是的，你可以这么理解，任何东西都会有层次结构，然后再往 .cs 之下探索将更有趣
it gets even more interesting, it turns into a class explorer.
它变成了一个类浏览器
Okay.
好的
These are not files, of course that's a property and that's a method.
这些不是文件，显然这是一个属性，而这是一个方法
But now we're blurring the lines and now you're really looking at conceptual bits of things
但现在我们正在逐步深入，你可以看到一些概念性的东西，而当你修改文件之后
as you make change those will update.
这些信息都将会更新
So that's something that you see in Visual Studio that you don't see in Visual Studio Code
因此，你可以在 Visual Studio 中看到一些在 Visual Studio Code 中不曾看到过的东西
I can do that with all my C# classes.
且我可以对我所有的 C# 类进行此操作
So remember before Startup and ConfigureServices and all that.
还记得之前的 Startup 和 ConfigureService 以及所有的这些嘛
-Yeah -Same kinda deal
-当然 -类似的
also things like our appsettings.json which we used earlier in the previous module for configuration.
像我们之前在上一个章节中用于配置的 appsettings.json
If there is something that has an environment, like appsettings.production.json or appsettings.json
如果在这还标明了环境，比如 appsettings.production.json 或 appsettings.json
that's something we didn't yet talk about.
那就是我们还没有谈到的东西
No.
确实没有
Remember before when I did that I commented that line out so that I could see
记得之前，我注释掉了一行，以便看到
The exception page, yeah.
异常页面，是嘛
Exceptions, where was that, do you remember where that was?
异常，那是在哪儿，你记得是什么地方吗？
Yeah, I believe it was in your Startup.
嗯，我猜在你的 Startup 里面
-There it is -Yeah
-它就在那里 -是的
So here's UseDeveloperExceptionPage and if you recall
所以这里就是 UseDeveloperExceptionPage ，如果你回想一下
it was if you're in development do that.
它只会在开发环境中执行
Every time we ran the thing it kept saying we were in production.
可每次我们运行的时候，它都是会显示我们正在生产环境中
Yes.
是的
I grew frustrated.
这让我非常伤心~
And I went just like that, which got me past that problem but isn't correct.
然后我就这样做了，这让我解决了这个问题，但并不是正确的做法
We're going right click, properties, and is it build or is it debug?
让我们右键，属性，它是在构建还是调试中？
-Go to -Debug
-转到 -调试
There we go and then you add it.
到这个页面后，你再添加它
Yeah, so the environment variable ASPNETCORE_ENVIRONMENT equals Development
是的，所以将环境变量 ASPNETCORE_ENVIRONMENT 设置为 Development
Is the thing that makes the difference.
会有所不同
So tying that back to configuration, you can have different configuration options.
将其与配置相关联，你可以拥有不同的配置选项
You can have appsettings.Whatever.
你可以有 appsettings.Whatever
And whatever, literally whatever, like foo.
whatever 就真的是任意内容，像 foo 也行
Anything
任何东西
Testing, staging.
测试，分期
Okay.
好的
Right, whatever makes you happy.
嗯，只要你高兴写什么都行
So in this case here, one appsettings.json, has some stuff in it.
在这种情况下，一个 appsettings.json 将包含一些东西
Looks like it's got, oops, wrong button.
看起来它有，哎呀，按错了
Some logging that we'll learn about a little later.
我们将在稍后再来了解日志记录
And then Development.Look at the difference between the two.
然后是 Development 的配置，看看两者之间的区别
One is set for Warning and one is set for Debug.
一个设置为 Warning，一个设置为 Debug
Wow, okay.
哇，原来这样啊
Right, so a little bit of information there.
对，那还有一些信息
So more sophisticated than what we had originally set up.
这比我们最初建立的要更复杂
Let's return over to Startup and see what else is different.
让我们回到 Startup ，看看还有什么不同
So we've got that configuration that we did before.
就像我们之前所做的一样，我们有 Configuration 对象
We've got services.AddMVC.
我们有 services.AddMVC
Here's an exception here, this is an interesting little bit of code right here.
在这有个异常处理，这是一小段有趣的代码
So if we're in development, show the exception page that I like as a developer.
如果我们正在开发中，就显示开发人员最喜爱的异常处理页面
Or if you're in production or really anything but development, we're just gonna show the error.
或者当你们正处于生产环境或除了开发之外的环境中时，我们将只显示这个错误
That way we don't give away our source code and show people stuff.
这样我们就不会泄露我们的源代码，也不会向外人展示一些东西
Now you had me use UseMVC before.
你在此之前让我用过 UseMVC
Yes.
是的
This one has a little bit more information with different routes.
这里包含了处理不同路由的用法
We'll talk about that another time.
我们会在其他章节中再来讨论
And then we've also got static files in case you wanted to pick a file.
然后我们使用了静态文件，以便你想要获取一个文件
Remember that couple of times we tried to pick up a file
请记住，有几次我们试图获取一个文件，但却被跳过了
and it was skipping right past it cuz we didn't put the at page?
就是因为我们没有在这使用它？
Yes.
是的
It would have served that file if it found it on disk, if we had said StaticFiles.
当我们使用了 StaticFiles 后，如果程序能在磁盘上找到这个文件，它就会提供该文件
So if we had added that line of code into the previous experiment it would have just worked?
那么，如果我们将这行代码添加到上一个试验中，它是否会起作用？
It wouldn't have worked.
它不会奏效
It would have picked the file up and served it to us.
它会找到文件并将其提供给我们
But it would have picked it up as a static file.
但它会把它当作一个静态文件
And that didn't work like it intended, okay.
好吧，这并不符合预期
And not as a Razor page and actually executed the code.
而不是作为 Razor 页面来执行代码
So the order of these things matter.
所以这些事情的顺序很重要
And also whether or not you want to run that or pick it up as a static file
比如你是想要运行它还是将其作为静态文件（比如 gif 或 html 页面）
like a gif or an html page, all right?
来提供，对吗？
So that's a little bit of a tour.
所有在这一次探索过程中
Am I missing anything?
我有漏掉什么吗？
I think that sounds good.
我觉得应该没了
That's good.
那很好
Actually one other point.
其实还有一点
Underneath wwwroot, that's where your static things go.
在 wwwroot 目录下，这些就是静态的文件
We've got our images there and our css.
我们有我们的图像和我们的 CSS
The pages, the static things are served out of root.
这些页面以及静态文件都是在 root 目录中
And then the pages for our razor pages app, it's located in Pages
然后我们的 Razor 页面，将位于 Pages 文件夹
But when I wanna have an image like /images, /something, it's served out of wwwroot
但是，当我想获得一个图片，比如 /images 或 /something ，这些都将由 wwwroot 提供
So, there is one thing that's new, is the view imports, layouts.
然后，这还有一个新的知识点，就是页面导入和布局
Good point.
说的好
So, remember when we were goofing around earlier, and over here we had our @page and we had @inject
还记得在我们早些试验的时候，在这儿我们使用了 @page 以及 @inject
and that wasn't enough, and then we needed an @using?
但这还不够，我们还需要使用 @using
And then suddenly we have more directives, then we had code?
然后突然我们还有了更多的指令，再然后我们还会有一些代码？
Yeah.
是啊
That was a little weird.
那有点奇怪
Well, you can do a thing called Viewimports which is all of that things that you want every page to have.
好吧，你可以创建一个名为Viewimports的文件，这些就是你希望每个页面都有的东西
Right, so we want every page to use this namespace.
是的，所以我们希望每个页面都使用这个命名空间
And every other one to, this is using a name space and this is the name space of those pages themselves.
而且对每个页面来说，这是使用名称空间，这是这些页面本身的名称空间
There's also a thing called tag helpers that we'll talk about in the intermediate today.
这还有一个叫做标签帮助器的东西，我们将在中间件中讨论
Yes we will.
是，我们会的
And then ViewStart is a piece of code, multiple lines.
然后 ViewStart 是一段多行代码
As many as you like, that runs for every view.
你可以写任意的代码，这些将在每个页面中运行
Okay.
好的
All right. So if every view needed to check someone's name, or check for cookies or whatever.
好吧，因此，如果每个视图都需要检查某人的姓名，或检查 cookie 或其他什么
It depends how you want to do things.
这取决于你想做什么
But these are the imports, all the different injects, all the different usings.
但这些就是导入，所有不同的注入，所有不同的引用
And this is the little bit of code you want.
这是你想要的一些代码
In this case here, it's setting a layout.
在这，它讲设置布局
That's like the main page, that every other page wraps around.
这就像主页一样，其他的任意页面都会包含在内
So here, _Layout.cshtml is a razor page that has the top level HTML, it has the head, it has the CSS.
所以在这里， _Layout.cshtml 是一个 Razor 页面，它包含了最外层的 html , head 以及 CSS
Probably has a footer somewhere.
可能在某个地方还有一个页脚
Yep, footer's down here.
是的，页脚在这里
There's some Bootstrap and some different JavaScript.
这有一些 Bootstrap 和一些不同的 JavaScript
And then your razor page is called the Body.
然后你的 Razor 页面被叫做 Body
And it's rendered right there.
它将会在这被渲染
It's rendered right there.
它就在那里呈现
So this is a good point actually.Let me do this.
这实际上是一个好主意，让我来试下
BEGIN BODY, END BODY, okay?
BEGIN BODY，END BODY，可以吗？
Okay.
可以
Let's run this.
让我们来运行一下吧
So this one is a little bigger of course than our previous application.
这比我们之前的应用程序要大一些
So it might take a moment to fire up.
所以可能需要一点时间才能启动
Okay and if you go to another one of the pages, let's say the homepage.
好的，如果你转到另一个页面，我们已经看过主页了
Good point.
好主意
This is the home page, let's go to About.
这是主页，我们去关于页面
Yeah it should be on hook.
是的，它应该也是一样
Okay.
对的
So that's everything that's outside, and this bit here would be
这就是外面的一切，而且这些将是来自于
Everything coming from the page.
一切都来自页面
Right here.
就在这儿
Yeah.
是的
So START MY PAGE, END MY PAGE.
试下 START MY PAGE ， END MY PAGE
-Make sense? -Yeah
-可以吗？ -可以
All right, cool.
很好，很酷
So I'm just undoing all of that, little control z,
然后我撤消这些，只需 Ctrl + z
and we will come back in a moment, and try to build something.
我们将很快就会回来，然后试着做一些东西
-Yeah -That is nontrivial.
-是的 -那是非常重要的
Exactly.
当然啦
And we'll probably make a couple mistakes.
而且我们可能会犯一些错误
And it happens.
它已经发生了
And hopefully we will learn.
希望我们能够学习些知识
And we appreciate you learning with us.
感谢你与我们一起学习
Thank you.
谢谢